<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-model href="../../derivatives/shelley-godwin-page.rnc"
            type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><surface xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:sga="http://sga.mith.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="ox-ms_abinger_c56-0005" ulx="0" uly="0" lrx="5088" lry="7082">
  <graphic url="../../images/ox/ox-ms_abinger_c56-0005.tif"/>
  <zone><line>Chapt. 2</line><line>Those events which materially influence our fu</line><line>ture
    destinies are often unused by slight an derive their origin from a tri</line><line>vial
      occurences. Strange as the statement of this simple fact</line>
    <line>may appear my fate had been Chemist Natu</line><line>ral Philosophy has is the genius that
      has</line><line> regulated my fate I wish desire therefore in this account</line><line>of my
        early years to state those facts which</line><line>led to my love foremost of that study first
          aqu predeliction for that science. When</line> I was eleven years old We all went on a party
    of pleasure to Thonan the baths near Thonan and were confined there<line/><line>to abrt obliged
      by the rain and The inclemen</line><line>cy of th eweather obliged us to remain a
        day</line><line> confined to the inn. In this house I chancd to find a fo volumes of the Works
          of Corne</line><line>lius Agrippa. And I opened it with apathy</line><line>but continued with
            enthusiasm. the theory that he attempted to demonstrate and the wonderful facts
            that</line><line>he relates chan soon changed this feeling into A new</line><line>light dawned
              upon my mind and I com</line><line>bounding with joy I communicated my discovery to my father.
                I cannot help here remark</line><line>ing the many opportunities parents have instructors
                  posess</line><line>of directing the attention of their pupils to</line><line>useful knowledge,
                    which they utterly neglect.</line><line>My father looked carefully at the title
                      page</line><line>of my book- Ah and said Ah! Cornelius</line><line> Agrippa!- My dear Victor
                        do not waste</line><line>your time upon this- it is sad trash.</line><line>If instead of this
                          remark or rather excla</line><line>mation my father had taken the pains to</line> expound lain
    to that the principles of
    </zone>
</surface>