<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?><?xml-model href="../../derivatives/shelley-godwin-page.rnc"
            type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl"
            href="../../xsl/page-proof.xsl"
        ?>
<surface xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:sga="http://sga.mith.org/ns/1.0"
    xml:id="ox-ms_abinger_c56-0132" ulx="0" uly="0" lrx="5078" lry="7304" partOf="ox-ms_abinger_c56">
    <graphic url="../../images/ox/ox-ms_abinger_c56-0132.tif"/>
    <zone type="main"> 
        <line>soon forgotten and we hasten from this semi-barbarous</line>
        
        <line>period to contemplate the glories of Greece <del>in</del><add>on</add> whose his-</line>
        
        <line>tory we shall find the <unclear>br</unclear> triumph of <unclear/> human nature</line>
        
        <line>may meditate with complacency and triumphe and in selecting</line> 
        
        <line>names &#x26; <unclear/> and by challenge its detractors with names and</line>
        
        <line>actions and summing up the <del>n</del> names &#x26; actions that orna</line>
        
        <line>men embellish the pages of history though through so long</line>
        
        <line>a series of years - Very very exciting! While that of Cyrus</line>
        
        who       their empire and founded his own on its ruins
        <line>conducted on principles of utility and benevolence endured</line>
        
        <line>through the lapse of many ages.</line>
        
        <line>C The m memory of by Cyrus is contemplated with pe</line>
        
        <line>culiar complacency by most historians. His y humanity &#x26;</line>
        
        <line>love of justice distinguishes to him from ^those other conquerors to</line>
        
        <line>whom ambition was the ruling motive. C Cyrus was edu</line>
        
        <line>cated in the strictest simplicity er early inured to fatigue</line>
        
        <line>and ^taught after the manners of the age, to consider glory as the</line>
        
        <line>as the great and desirable bourne to which every virtu</line>
        
        <line>ous man ought to direct his <del>steps</del><add>exertions</add>. But the natural</line>
        
        <line>mildness of his disposition led him the ?ather to seek for</line>
        
        <line>honour in the pardon than in the punishment of his</line> 
        
        <line>enemies. and if he conquered it was to bestow a more and</line> 
        
        <line>his conquests ^often appeared to f the fallen nation<del>s</del> as in light</line>
        
        <line>of a blessing rather than a curse. The romance with which</line>
        
        <line>Xenophon has embellished the history of this prince and</line>
        
        <line>the numerous ane anecdotes which he has either accor</line>
        
        <line>invented in his honour renders as apparent by better</line>
        
        <line>acquainted with the character of this monarch than of</line>
        
        <line>any other of ancient times. Inmemorable anecdotes are</line>
        
        <line>recorded of his virtue and mildness by ???? Xenophon</line>
        
        <line>but unfortunately this history must be <del>looked upon</del> ^ujouded rather</line>
        
        <line>as a romance than the real biography of the man; for al</line>
        
        <line>through tradition might probably preserve several of the</line>
        
        <line>private actions of so distinguished a man prince it e is</line>
        
        <line>not probable that in ea yet the minuteness &#x26; egularity</line>
        
        <line>of detail which embellishes the ^narrations of ther ???? must be entirely</line>
        
        <line>????ed upon entirely as the in vention of the historian writer. How</line>
        
        <line>??? The extent of our ??? We are ?????utterly entirely incapa</line>
        
    </zone>
</surface>
