<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model
  href="../../derivatives/shelley-godwin-page.rnc"
  type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<surface partOf="ox-ms_abinger_c57"
  xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
  xmlns:sga="http://sga.mith.org/ns/1.0"
  xml:id="ox-ms_abinger_c57-0081"
  ulx="0" uly="0" lrx="5138" lry="7032">
  <graphic url="../../images/ox/ox-ms_abinger_c57-0081.tif"/>
    <zone type="pagination"> 101
    </zone>
  <zone type="pagination">41 <mod hand="unknown"></mod></zone>
  <zone type="main">
    <line>But it is this gloom which appears to have taken</line>
    <line>too strong a hold of your mind that I wish to dissi</line>
    <line>pate. Tell me therefore whether you object to an imme</line>
    <line>diate solemnization of the marriage. We have been unfor</line>
    <line><add place="superlinear"><del><unclear reason="smudged">tunate</unclear></del></add>tunate, and recent events have drawn us from that</line>
    <line>every day tranquillity <del>so necess</del> befitting my years and</line>
    <line>infirmities. You are younger yet I do not suppose, possess</line>
    <line>ed as you are of a competent fortune that an early</line>
    <line>marriage would at all interfere with any future plans</line>
    <line>of honour and utility <add place="superlinear"><mod hand="PBS">that</mod>you may have formed</add><del rend="strikethrough">Yet</del>Do not suppose however that</line>
    <line>I wish to dictate happiness to you or that a</line>
    <line>delay on your part would cause me any <add place="superlinear" hand="PBS">serious</add> uneasi</line>
    <line>ness; Interpret my words with candour and answer</line>
    <line>me I conjure you with confidence and sincerity.</line>
    <milestone unit="paragraph"/>
    <line>I listened to my father in silence and remained</line>
    <line><add place="superlinear">for</add>sometime without offering any reply. I revolved</line>
    <line>rapidly in my mind a multitude of <mod type="subst"><del rend="strikethrough">ideas</del><add place="superlinear">thoughts</add></mod> and</line>
    <line><del rend="strikethrough">d</del> endeavoured to come to some conclusion. Alas!</line>
    <line>to me the idea of an immediate union with my</line>
    <line>cousin was one of horror and dismay. I was bound by</line>
    <line>a solemn promise which I had not yet fufilled and</line>
    <line>dared not break; or if I did what manifold mise</line>
    <line>ries might not impend over me and my devo</line>
    <line>ted family! <del rend="strikethrough">And</del> could I enter into a festival with</line>
    <line>this deadly weight yet hanging round my neck and</line>
    <line>bowing me to the ground. <del rend="strikethrough">No, <add place="superlinear"><mod hand="PBS">that</mod></add>I could not endure</del></line>
    <line><del>that</del><del>and therefore resolved to</del><add place="superlinear"><mod hand="PBS">I <unclear>must</unclear></mod></add> perform my engage</line>
    <line>ment and let the monster depart with his mate</line>
  </zone>
</surface>

