<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?><?xml-model href="../../derivatives/shelley-godwin-page.rnc"
            type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl"
            href="../../xsl/page-proof.xsl"
        ?>
<surface xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:sga="http://sga.mith.org/ns/1.0"
  xml:id="ox-ms_abinger_c57-0189" ulx="0" uly="0" lrx="5138" lry="7316"
  partOf="#ox-ms_abinger_c57-0189">
  <graphic url="../../images/ox/ox-ms_abinger_c57-0189.tif"/>
  <zone type="library">95 (<unclear/>)</zone>
  <zone type="main">
    <milestone unit="tei:p"/><line>The mames of <damage agent="tear"><unclear/></damage> a
      Simiramis, sovereigns of Babylon are</line>
    <line>preserved by that bloody hallo with glory and victory always decora<damage agent="tear"
        ><unclear/></damage></line>
    <line>its worshippers; but the effects of their conquest were but mom<damage agent="tear"
        >e</damage></line>
    <line>tary and gave way before the rapid advances of Cyrus whose</line>
    <line>warfare conducted on principles of untility and benevolence</line>
    <line>edured<!-- encoder unsure of this reading --> through the lapse of many ages</line>
    <milestone unit="tei:p"/><line>The memory of Cyrus is contemplated with peculiar</line>
    <line>complacency by <del rend="strikethrough">many</del> most historians. His humanity and
      love</line>
    <line>of justice distinguish<add place="intralinear">es</add> him those other conquerors to
      whom</line>
    <line>ambition<add place="sublinear"><metamark>&#x2038;</metamark></add>
      <add place="superlinear">is</add>
      <del rend="strikethrough">was</del> the ruling motive. Cyrus was educated in the</line>
    <line>strictest simplicity, <del rend="strikethrough">and</del> early
      enured<!-- encoder unsure of this reading --> to fatigue and taught</line>
    <line>after the manners of <del rend="strikethrough">the</del><add place="sublinear"
          ><metamark>&#x2038;</metamark></add>
      <add place="superlinear">his</add> age, to consider glory as the great &#x26;</line>
    <line>desirable bourne towards which every virtuous man ought</line>
    <line>to direct his exertions But the natural <del rend="strikethrough">mil</del> mildness of
      his</line>
    <line>disposition let him the rather to seek for honour in the <damage agent="tear"
        ><unclear/></damage></line>
    <line>don than in the punishment of his enemies; and his <damage agent="tear"
        ><unclear/></damage></line>
    <line>often appeared to the fallen nation rather in the light of <damage agent="tear"
        ><unclear/></damage></line>
    <line>blessing than a curse. Innumerable anecdotes are <damage agent="tear"
      ><unclear/></damage></line>
    <line>of his virtue and wisdom by Xenephon but this history, <damage agent="tear"
        ><unclear/></damage></line>
    <line>tunately must be regarded as a romance rather than the real</line>
    <line>biography of the man: for although tradition might probably</line>
    <line>preserve several <del rend="strikethrough">anecdotes</del> of the private actions of
      so</line>
    <line>celebrated a prince yet the minuteness &#x26; regularity of detail</line>
    <line><del rend="strikethrough">w</del> which embellishes the narratives of the Cyropedia
      must</line>
    <line>be solely attributed to the invention of its author and there</line>
    <line>are no rational grounds by which we can regulate the ex</line>
    <line>tent of credit due to the historian of <del rend="strikethrough">Cy</del> Cyrus. The
      anecdotes</line>
    <line>however that are perserved of him chiefly relate to the generous</line>
    <line>pardon of his prisoners of war, a mode of proceeding that</line>
    <line>wonderfully facillitated his conquest so that he was still young</line>
    <line>when he became possessed of the Babylonish Empire. From</line>
    <line>this time he was principally occupied in the cares of govern</line>
    <line>ment which he established on a very arbitrary <del rend="strikethrough">b</del>
      footing</line>
    <line>leaving to his sucessors a despotic authority over a people</line>
    <line><damage agent="tear"><unclear/></damage> whose courage was destroyed by slavery and</line>
  </zone>
</surface>
